A Guide to the Papers of John Powell, 1888-1978, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I.: Correspondence
  - Subseries A.: Correspondence of John and Louise Powell
    - Section 1.: Chronological Correspondence
      - Correspondence, February 1934, 108 items. (Box-folder 9:2)
        Letters from John Powell to: [Bernice Chausler]; Mrs. [Nancy] Baldwin; Mr. [Horton] Barker; C. C. Cappel; John Crowder; Mr. [Edward H.] Droop; Miss Edmunds; [Elizabeth]; Mrs. Fergus; Mr. [M. W.] Galloway; Mrs. [Texas] Gladden; H. W. Gray; Mr. [I. G.]Greer; Mr. Huffman; Vera Bull Hull; J. B. Hunt; Mr. Johnston; Verbon E. Kemp; Hans Kindler; Miss Kinscella; Ernest LaPrade; Mrs. Lent; Mrs. [Jean] Lohman; Mrs. McCartney; Daniel Gregory and Mary Mason; Mrs. Morris; Alfreda Peel; Mr. [Jack] Reedy; Miss Shaffer; C. B. Wohlford.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: [Allan]; Mrs. [Arthur O.] Choate; Mr. Galloway; Mrs. Gladden; Mr. [I. G.] Greer; Mr. Holloway; Miss Lovenan; Miss MacDonald; Mr. Manning; Miss [Sallie Willie] Sterling; [Little Maria].
      - Correspondence, March 1934, 88 items. (Box-folder 9:3)
        Correspondents include Orlando Amburger; Ada Benelli; John L. Bladon to C. W. Creger; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Annabel Morris Buchanan to choral director; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Richard Crane; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Verbon E. Kemp; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Roy Nichols, Raimonde Aubrey, Ruth Thomas, Elizabeth Starritt, Miss Constance Wardle; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Mr. Nelson; Grace [Potter Carroll]; Mrs. W. H. Carruth; Eunice Cheatham; Clarence C. Coward; John Crowder; Juliet Fauntleroy; Phyllis Fergus; Annie Friedberg; Sallie Le Grande; Virginia C. Harwood; Mary Evan Holman; L. B. Houff; J. M. Hunt; [Jacob]; Jess Johnston; Verbon E. Kemp to Annabel Morris Buchanan; Hans Kindler; Ludwig Koch; Ernest LaPrade; A. H. Larson; Helen S. Leavitt; Mrs. Stanley Lee; Jean Lohman; Elizabeth Warren Magruder Daniel Gregory Mason; T. Tertius Noble; Julia Fuqua Ober; C. A. Overton to R. H. Miller; R. F. Nelson; C. A. Overton; C. A. Overton to F. R. Rector; C. A. Overton to G. P. Blackwell; Mrs. Mattie Pickreal; Jack Reedy; Melville Smith; Mrs. Leonard N. Snedeker; Ruby Smith Stahl; Lamar Stringfield; Mrs. Mabel Tankard; Donald Withycomb to H. M. Curtler.
        Letters from John Powell to: Mrs. Nancy Baldwin; Council Cruise; Frank [Warrington Dawson]; J. M. Hunt; Mr. Johnston; Mr. [Keezee]; Ernest LaPrade; Miss Helen S. Leavitt; Jean Lohman; Mr. Morris; Mr. [Jack] Reedy; Mrs. Williamson.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Mrs. [Orlando] Amburger; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Annabel Morris Buchanan to choral director; [children, nieces?]; Grace [Potter Carroll]; Mrs. [Phyllis] Fergus; Miss [Virginia] Harwood; Miss Kettering; Mr. Kramer; [Margaret]; Mrs. Robertson; Aunt Betty Smith; [dearest little thing].
      - Correspondence, March 1934, 86 items. (Box-folder 9:4)
        Correspondents include Raimonde Aubrey; Dr. Aaron Barnett; [Coeuraad V. Bos]; Edna G. Brown; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Richard Crane; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Hans Kindler; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Mr. Morris; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Roy Nichols; Annabel Morris Buchanan to W.H. Sage; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Richard Crane, John Powell, Verbon E. Kemp, Winston Wilkinson; Phillips Carlin; Mrs. Arthur O. Choate; Catherine Robertson Coleman; Francis Warrington Dawson; Ruth M. Ferry; Ernest Hutcheson, Juilliard School of Music; George [Pullen Jackson]; Douglas Kennedy, Director, English Folk Dance & Song Society; Verbon E. Kemp to Annabel Morris Buchanan; Verbon E. Kemp to Richard Crane; Hans Kindler; Helen S. Leavitt; L. Lunkford; W. S. Martin; Daniel Gregory Mason; John M. Morris; Robert F. Nelson; Richard Newman; Herbert Goff Ricker; Don Rockwell; F. E. Sanders; George M. Small; Alice B. Steuart; Louisa S. Stratian; Elizabeth Stuart; Lucille Walton; Marie Wilkinson.
        Letters from John Powell to: Annabel Morris Buchanan; Mr. Hall; Hans Kindler; Miss [Helen S. ] Leavitt; Dr. [T. Tertius] Noble; Mr. [Don] Rockwell; Mrs. Strickler.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Mr. Chase; Julia [Fuqua Ober]; Mr. Porterfield; Mrs. Stahl; Lamar [Stringfield].
      - Correspondence, January-March 1934, 76 items. (Box-folder 9:5)
        Correspondents include Claude L. Bourcier; Elizabeth Burchenal; Emmeline Burleigh; C. C. Cappel; C. J. Carrier; Mary Izant Couch; Emma C. Dimmock; May Edmonds; Phyllus Fergus; May Gadd; I. G. Greer; William J. Holloway; Mary Howe; Elsie Illingworth; Gertrude Ingles; George Pullen Jackson; Helen Gertrude Kinscella; Ernest LaPrade; Elizabeth McCartney; Miss Pearl McDonald; Daniel Gregory Mason; Mary Mason; Sylvia Meyer; Ellen Moberg; Margaret Munn; Edith Ballinger Price; W. Forbes Robertson, The Beacon Press; Mary V. Robertson; Milton C. Smith; Henry Sotheran, LTD.; Elizabeth L. Stuart; Randall Thompson; Mellicent Wheeler; Marie Wilkinson; Emma C. Wimock. Louise Powell to: [Aunt Emma]; Ernest LaPrade; [Louise]; Mary Smyth, Henry Sotheran, LTD.
      - Correspondence, April 1934, 55 items. (Box-folder 9:6)
      - Correspondence, April 1934, 58 items. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Correspondents included Raimonde Aubrey; Sidney Banks, The Cavalier, Virginia Beach; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Verbon E. Kemp and Mr. Nelson; C. C. Cappel; Grace Potter Carroll; Jim Chisholm, Richard Crane; Bertha L. Crowder; Francis Warrington Dawson; Miss Drinker; Marjorie Edgar; Juliet Fauntleroy; Ruth M. Ferry; George Fischer; Polly Hunter; George Pullen Jackson; Verbon E. Kemp; Hans Kindler; Wythe Leigh Kinsolving; Arnold Kruckman;; Ernest LaPrade; Marks Levine; Jean Lohman; Daniel Gregory Mason; Robert F. Nelson; T. Tertius Noble; W. Allen Perkins, attorney for the purchase of their new Charlottesville home, Longways; W. Appleby Robinson to Dr. T. Tertius Noble; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; Maurice Tyler; C. B. Wohlford.
        Letters from John Powell to: C. C. Cappel; Miss Drinker; George Fischer; George Pullen Jackson; Ernest LaPrade; Marks Levine; Dr. T. Tertius Noble.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Mr. [J. M. or Sailor Dad] Hunt; C. B. Wohlford.
      - Correspondence, May 1934, 51 items. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Correspondents include Annabel Morris Buchanan; May Ball; May S. Brower; Mr. and Mrs. Carroll; Mr. and Mrs. Copeland; Louise Findlay; Mrs. George Ferguson Finnie; C. L. Graves; H. W. Gray Co.; Bassett Hough toast to Daniel Gregory Mason; William E. Hudson; Ernest Hutcheson; Verbon E. Kemp; George Pullen Jackson; John Preston McConnell; Daniel Gregory Mason; F. Midge; T. Michaux Moody; Green Peyton; Mary V. Robertson to Annabel Morris Buchanan; Carleton D. Smith, WMAL Radio concerning the White House Folk Concert; Robert L. Stearns; Mrs. Elsie Strickler, Buena Vista Music Club; Lamar Stringfield; Grace Warding; Maria Wilkinson.
        Letters from John Powell to: Miss Burchenal; Mr. Koch; Ernest LaPrade; Miss Lunkford; Mrs. [Mattie] Pickreal; Mr. Smith; Miss Stackhouse.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Mrs. Coleman; Miss Drennan; Mrs. Finnie; Mr. Henna; Christine [Kelper]; Verbon E. Kemp; Miss Robertson; Miss Sanders.
      - Correspondence, May 1934, 67 items. (Box-folder 9:9)
        Raimonde Aubrey; Horton Barker; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Mr. Crane; Annabel Morris Buchanan to the editor, Richmond Times-Dispatch; Carrol W. Cole, violinist; Louise Findlay; Mrs. William Arms Fisher; George Fischer; [Elane] B. Hall, G. Schirmer, Inc.; Alexander B. Hill; Alice Aylett Hoge; J. M. Hunt [Sailor Dad]; Ernest Hutcheson; Mrs. Agnes Jardine; Verbon E. Kemp; Eunice Kettering; Ellen H. Knox; Ernest LaPrade; Marks Levine; Helen S. Leavitt; Jean Lohman; Emilie G. McLaughlin; Eric F. Massey; H. David [Murray]; C. A. Overton to E. L. Repass; W. Allan Perkins; Sallie Stephens Perkins; Mr. Porterfield, Mountain Lake Hotel; George Floyd Rogers; Katharine K. Rucker; Thomas B. Scott; Lamar Stringfield; Bill White; Marie Wilkinson; C. B. Wohlford.
        Letters from John Powell: Mrs. Benton; Mr. Church; Louise [Findlay]; Mrs. Helm; J. M. Hunt [Sailor Dad];Ernest LaPrade; Mr. Smith; C. B. Wohlford.
        Letters from Louise Powell: Mrs. Norris; Edna [Turpin].
      - Correspondence, June-July 1934, 90 items. (Box-folder 10:1)
        John Powell is invited to be on the Olympic Committee for the 1936 games; Powell is unhappy with his representation from NBC and corresponds with Edward Stettinius, Jr. who agrees to talk to NBC; John Powell works with the University of Virginia to set up summer classes on folk music.
        Correspondents include Horton Barker; Annabel Morris Buchanan to John R. Hutcheson; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Mr. Nelson; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Mr. Starnes; Richard Chase; Allen Cleaton, The Evening Star; George Fischer; George Fischer to Mrs. Harrison Robertson [Mary V.?] Donald S. Gates; Mrs. H. E. Hartzell; Lyla Colonna Hill; William E. Hudson; George Pullen Jackson; Jess Johnston; Henry Junge; Ernest LaPrade; Helen S. Leavitt; John Preston McConnell; John Preston McConnell to John Blakemore; Lois Miller; T. Tertius Noble; Sylvia Slocum, American Country Life Association; Lamar Stringfield; Mabelle S. Wall, The Atlanta Journal; Mr. and Mrs. C. B. Wohlford.
        Letters from John Powell: Annabel Morris Buchanan; Miss Ruth [Burchenal]; George Fischer; Mrs. Agnes Jardine; Jess Johnston.
        Letters from Louise Powell: Horton Barker; Boston Musical and Educational Bureau Annabel Morris Buchanan; Richard Chase; [George] Fischer; Maimie; Alma [Hartwell]; William E. Hudson; Ernest LaPrade; Miss Miller; Mrs. Morrill; Mr. Porterfield; Erich Rath; Lamar Stringfield; Mr. [Alexander] Weddell.
      - Correspondence, August-September 1934, 81 items. (Box-folder 10:2)
        Correspondents include Leiter der Kultur-Abteilung; Buda Baker; Inez E. Bauman; John A. Blakemore; John A. Blakemore to Winston Wilkinson; Katy Robertson Booker; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Arthur Kyle Davis; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Mrs. W. M. Walker; Mrs. Betty Brockenbrough; Kanuga Bugle; Georgia Richard Chase; Dunn Coggin; Eugene Craft; Samuel Feldman; George Fischer; R. W. Gordon; Dr. Henry Hadley, Association for American Composers and Conductors; Dr. Howard Hanson, Eastman School of Music; J. M. [Sailor Dad] Hunt; George Pullen Jackson; Mrs. Agnes Jardine; Lorna. R. Johnston, Robert E. Lee Week; William K. Jones; Mrs. L. Pendleton MacCartney; Iola J. Maloney, The Hopewell Woman's Club; Daniel Gregory Mason; Martha M. Murdoch; Grace Nylon, The Musical Courier; Peter Temple Peorine; Mr. Porterfield; Marquerite Potter, New York Madrigal Society; Charles S. Powell, genealogy; George King Raudenbush, Harrisburg Symphony Orchestra; Virginia Richardson, folksongs; Mary V. Robertson; Hilton Rufty; George Ryall; F. E. Sanders; Ethel M. Smith, Ginn & Co; T. E. Starnes, Secretary, Giles County Chamber of Commerce; Lamar Stringfield; E. Maud Veitch, played Powell composition at the World's Fair; John Vincent; Mabelle S. Wall, The Atlanta Journal; Mr. and Mrs. C. B. Wohlford.
        Letters from John Powell: Mr. Diehl; Loren R. Johnston, Robert E. Lee Week; Mr.[William K.] Jones; Mr. Koch; Helen S. Leavitt; Marks Levine; Mrs. [Iola] Maloney; Mr. George King Raudenbush
        Letters from Louise Powell: Annabel Morris Buchanan; Mrs. Crockett; Mr. [Samuel] Feldman; Mrs. [Lyla Colonna] Hill.
      - Correspondence, October-November 1934, 78 items. (Box-folder 10:3)
        Correspondents include Eileen G. Anderson; Rocco de Beneditto; John Ingram Brookes, State Teachers College, Radford; Richard Chase; M. Estes Cocke, Hollins College; Walter Damrosch, Musicians Emergency Fund; Mrs. George C. Eichhorn; Lydia F. [Everest]; David Ewen; Edgar A. Ewing, Music Club of Greensboro; George Fischer; Mrs. Claire Gallup; Ed Gooderow; Dr. Howard Hanson; George Hoffman; D. R. Hunt, National Emergency Council; George Pullen Jackson; Mrs. Agnes Jardine; Verbon E. Kemp; Ernest LaPrade; Helen S. Leavitt; Marks Levine, NBC; John Preston McConnell; Gertrude McCormick; Dorothy Meyer, NBC; John Lloyd Newcomb, President, University of Virginia; Richard Newman; Julia Fuqua Ober; Mrs. Blandie Pollard; A. J. Powers, G. Schirmer, Inc.; Harry Rogers Pratt; Erich Rath; George King Raudenbush; Claire R. Reis, The League of Composers; William Gregory Rennolds; B. C. Randolph, Hollins College; Lamar Stringfield; Miss Mercye Tucker; Mrs. Gertrude Wollner.
        Letters from John Powell to: Mr. Walter Damrosch; Mr. [George] Fischer; Dr. [Howard] Hanson; Mr. Williams Jones; Mrs. [Iola] Maloney; John Lloyd Newcomb; Mrs. Dorothy Meyer; Mr. [A. J.] Powers; Mr. [William Gregory] Rennolds; Miss [Mercye] Tucker; Mrs. [Gertrude] Wollner.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Miss [Eileen G] Anderson; Boston Music Company; George Pullen Jackson; Marks Levine; Mr. Merrink; Julia Fuqua Ober; Mr. Erich Rath.
      - Correspondence, December 1934, 32 items. (Box-folder 10:4)
        Correspondents include Ivor Aycock; May Ball; Carrupt, G. Schirmer, Inc.; M. Estes Cocke; Elizabeth M. Colovirus; Richard Copley, Steinway & Sons; Helen Colley, G. Schirmer, Inc.; Charles E. Griffith, music editor; Marquerite V. Hood, State of Montana Public Instruction; George Pullen Jackson; W. B. James, Jr.; Mrs. Agnes Jardine; Jess Johnston; Helen S. Leavitt; Daniel Gregory Mason; Henry Allen Moe; Pitts Sanborn, Radio Institute of the Audible Arts; Erich Rath; Edna Turpin; Charles G. Vardell, composer, Salem College; John Vincent; Marie and Winston Wilkinson.
        Letters from John Powell to: Daniel Gregory Mason.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Mrs. Agnes Jardine (symphony is not ready for Biennial Concert).
      - Correspondence, April-December 1934, 75 items. (Box-folder 10:5)
        Correspondents include Raimonde Aubrey; Ivor Aycock; B. H. Blackwell; Elizabeth S. Boocock; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Charlotte E. Burleigh; Emmaline Burleigh; Anne Chamberlayne; Lelia Claybrook; M. Estes Cocke, Hollins College; Alice Crockette; Gertrude Drinker; Ellen J. Edmonds; Louise Greely; Alma Gray Hartwell; W. Heffer & Sons; George Pullen Jackson; Bernice Kausler; Verbon E. Kemp; Ernest LaPrade; William Stapleton Long; [Lydia]; W. H. Lowdermilk & Co.; Gertrude McCormack; Mary Mason; Margaret Munn; Lita F. Norell; [Peachy]; Sallie Stephens Perkins; Mr. Porterfield; Mr. Porterfield to Mrs. J. S. Brockenbrough; Erich Rath; Mary V. Robertson; Luise Sillcox; Henry Sotheran, LTD.; Ruby Stahl; Elsie C. Strickler, Buena Vista Music Club; Rosa Tucker; Elizabeth Twaddell; Anne R. Wayland; Mellicent Wheeler; Marie Wilkinson; Lilly Logan Worrill.
        Louise Powell to: Mr. Cocke; Louise [Greelby]; Aunt Charlotte, Aunt Emmeline and Aunt Mellicent.
      - Correspondence, January 1935, 95 items. (Box-folder 10:6)
        Correspondents include Raimonde Aubrey; F. C. Adler, G. Schirmer, Inc.; Mrs. Alice Bergen; Eddy Brown, singer; Sarah E. Coleman; Helen Colley, G. Schirmer, Inc.; Richard Chase; Karl Dorr, music teacher; George Engles; Mary Fishburne, student; Marks Levine; Daniel Gregory Mason; Maurice Matteson; R. L. Porrier; A. J. Powers, G. Schirmer, Inc.; B. C. Randolph; Frederick L. Redefer, Progressive Education Association; Harold Reeves, bookseller; T. E. Starnes; O. C. Stone, Everett Piano Company; Lamar Stringfield; Mabel Tuttle; John Vincent; Winston Wilkinson; Gertrude Wollner; O. O. Young, Galesburg Public Schools.
        Letters from John Powell to: Eddy Brown; Miss Helen Colley; Miss Colovirus; [Ginsie]; Mr. Gordon; Mr. Hilbert, Courier Account; Mr. W. B. James, Jr.; Marks Levine; Mr. [Maurice] Matteson, Southeastern Folklore Society; Mr. Merriman; Miss [Helen] Moberg; Mr. Riker; Mr. Smith; Mrs. Gertude Wollner; O.O. Young.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Raimonde Aubrey; Mr. [Eddy] Brown; Richard Chase; Miss Helen Colley; Miss Mary Fishburne; [Mary and Stanley] Gates; Mr. [Charles E.] Griffith; Mr. [George] Hoffman; George Pullen Jackson; Mrs. Agnes Jardine; Mr. [Jess] Johnston; Ernest LaPrade; Miss [Helen S.] Leavitt; Dr. [John Preston] McConnell; Daniel Gregory Mason; [Dr. T. Tertius] Noble; A. J. Powers; Mr. [Frederick L.] Redefer; Lamar Stringfield; Nedda [Edna Turpin]; Mr. [Charles G.] Vardell; Mr. Wilson.
      - Correspondence, February 1935, 41 items. (Box-folder 10:7)
        Correspondents include Nancy Bruce; Kathryn Daniel; Alice Dukes; Wakeman [Frudeuly]; Weston S. Gales; William C. Gassner; Russell G. Harris; Charles A.[Iler]; George Pullen Jackson; Maud Karpeles; Edgar Stillman Kelley; Margaret Munn; L. Massie; Maurice Matteson; Mrs. Helen Harrison Mills; John O. Moroso; Katherine B. Peeples; Edith H. Pinchbeck; F. E. Sanders; Charles H. Sherrill.
        Letters from John Powell: Mr. [Eddy] Brown; Mr. [Charles E.] Griffith; Miss Harshbarger; Mr. [Maurice] Matteson; Mr. Smith.
      - Correspondence, March 1935, 57 items. (Box-folder 10:8)
        Correspondents include Isabel Baker; [Anold A. Bolen]; Lillian Britt; Eddy Brown; Elizabeth Burchenal; Norman Bel Geddes; Carrupt, G. Schirmer, Inc.; Richard Chase;; Mrs. Arthur O. Choate; Rebecca [Creshmare]; Elizabeth C. Davenport; W. D. Flanders, Federal Housing Administration; Mrs. J. Elliot Gould, Spencer Conservatory of Music; Leroy Hodges; Kate Dalliban Johns; Helen L. Kaufmann; Ernest LaPrade; Helen S. Leavitt; Dr. Theodor Lewald and American Olympic Association; J. Clarendon McClure; Maurice Matteson; Patricia O'Brien; Elise Paget; Mrs. Fred C. Parks; John Powell (namesake); Harry Roger Pratt; Allan [Sly]; Reed Smith; Sallie B. Steele; Mabel T. Taylor; J. B. Wells; Jean Wygal.
        Letters from John Powell to: Mrs. [Isabel] Baker; Walter Damrosch; Mrs. Dupont; Mr. [Henry Allen] Moe; Mrs. [Mabel T.] Taylor.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Mrs. Bruce; Alice [Dukes]; Mr. [William C.] Gassner; George [Pullen Jackson]; Chrystl [Kerry]; Mr. [Osbourne] McConathy.
      - Correspondence, April 1935, 63 items. (Box-folder 10:9)
        Correspondents include Annabel Morris Buchanan; E. M. Cameron, Jr., Delta Phi Fraternity; James D. Chapman; Richard Chase; Elsie Illingworth; Arthur G. Freeland, Delta Phi Fraternity; Susan H. Gilman, English Folk Dance Society of America; Sidney B. Hall to Dr. Charles G. Maphis; George H. Hilbert; Frederik Holmberg, Dean, University of Oklahoma; William E. Hudson; Helen L. Kaufmann; William Kozlenko; Ernest LaPrade; Charles G. Maphis, Dean, University of Virginia Summer Quarter; [Margaret]; Daniel Gregory Mason; E. C. Mills; Mrs. Margaret Munn; John Lloyd Newcomb; Clairborne Pope, Delta Phi Fraternity; Virginia Richardson; G. Schirmer, Inc.; R. V. Shanlin, Jr.; George M. Small, College of William and Mary; Reed Smith; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; Ruth M. Stevenson; Mabel T. Taylor; [Grace] Vanamee; Karl Wecker; Winston Wilkinson.
        Letters from John Powell to: [Mssrs Breitkopf and Haentel]; Dr. Walter Damrosch; Arthur Figelair; Mr. [George H.] Hilbert; Miss Illingworth; Ernest LaPrade; Helen S. Leavitt; Dr. Charles Maphis; [Maurice] Matteson; Miss [Helen] Moberg; John Lloyd Newcomb; Dr. [Reed] Smith; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; Mr. Terwilliger.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Mr. Gilbert; Mrs. [Helen L.] Kaufman; Mr. [William] Kozlenko; Ernest LaPrade; Mr. [Osbourne] McConathy; Nedda [Edna Turpin].
      - Correspondence, May 1935, 66 items. (Box-folder 11:1)
        Correspondence includes F. C. Adler; Sarah F. Brandes; C. C. Cappel; Mary C. Carter; Adele Van [Naue] Clarke; Richard Crane; Mary J. Evans; Charles E. Garrett; Charles E. Griffith to Dr. Charles Maphis; Charles E. Griffith to Dr. Sidney B. Hall; Russell G. Harris; Mrs. Lelia Gray Harrison; Frances Epes Hooper; Elsie Illingworth; Hans Kindler; Ernest LaPrade; Helen S. Leavitt; Arnold L. Lovejoy; Audrey McMahon; Charles G. Maphis; [Margaret]; Walter C. Mercer; Richard Newman; Littleton W. Parks, Delta Phi Fraternity; J. F. Repass; Mrs. Joseph K. Shoemaker, Jr.; [Mauren Van Slealsalin]; Henry C. Whitehead; Winston Wilkinson.
        Letters from John Powell to: [Dr. Baker]; [Douglas]; George Engle; Mr. [Charles E.] Griffith; Mr.[George H.] Hilbert; Mr. Jaffe; Hans Kindler; Ernest LaPrade; Helen S. Leavitt; Mr. [Arnold L.] Lovejoy; Mrs. [J. F.] Repass; Dr. Reed Smith; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; Mr. Wecker.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Miss Brandee; Miss [Adele] Clarke; Miss [Mary] Gadd; Mrs. Agnes Jardine; Miss [Maud] Karpeles; Miss Helen S. Leavitt; Mr. [T. E.] Starnes; Mary Tucker.
      - Correspondence, June 1935, 55 items. (Box-folder 11:2)
        Correspondents include F. C. Adler; C. C. Cappel; G. Chandler, Jr.; G. Wingfield [Coevy]; Allen Eaton; George Engle; Reverend Harry W. Foot; Arthur G. Freeland; Mary E. Gadd; Charles E. Griffith; Leroy Hodges; William E. Hudson; George Pullen Jackson; Helen S. Leavitt; Arnold L. Lovejoy; Wallace R. Magill, NBC; [G.] McCormick; Audrey McMahon; Julia Fuqua Ober; Ola B. Repass; Gustave Reese; Frederick W. Rublin; Mrs. Julia C. Saunders; Dorothy Scott; Cecil Carr Smith; Reed Smith; Yvonne de Treville; Mrs. Mercye Tucker; Marie and Winston Wilkinson.
        Letters from John Powell to: F. C. Adler; C. C. Cappel; George Engle; Mary Gates; Dr. [William E.] Hudson; Ernest LaPrade; Marks Levine; Mr. McMahon; Mr. Millar; Mrs. Puides; Gustave Reese; Miss [Edna] Shaeffer.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Mr. Leckner; Mrs. [Ola B.] Repass.
      - Correspondence, July-August 1935, 105 items. (Box-folder 11:3)
        Correspondents include F. C. Adler; Mrs. William Bacon; Frank Baer; May Ball; Avery Brundage; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Annabel Morris Buchanan to Dr. John Finley Willimmson; C. C. Cappel; Robert Carter; Richard Chase; Mrs. Dorothy Chitwood; James Francis Cooke; George Fischer; Charles C. Fleming; Alexander Haas, NBC; Miss Louise P. Hawley; Maruerite Cartwight Hawthorne; Leroy Hodges; Elsie Illingworth; George Pullen Jackson to Annabel Morris Buchanan; Jess Johnston; Elizabeth Kirkpatrick Jones; Helen L. Kaufmann; Ernest LaPrade; Helen S. Leavitt; Marks Levine; Elizabeth McCartney; John Preston McConnell; John Lloyd Newcomb; Iola Nichols; H. T. Van Nostrand, Jr., realtor; Amy W. Osborne; Sallie Stephens Perkinson; Mr. Porrier, NBC; Mr. Porterfield; Gustave Reese; Mrs. J. F. Repass; J. Albert Riker; Irma Ringe; Louise Kimball Robey; Johnny Russell; George Schaun; Edna Shaeffer; Nikolai Sokoloff; T. E. Starnes; Nina R. Swann; William Tuchman; Mabel Tuttle; Aurelia Walford; Constance Wardle; Lillian [Weast Terrie]; Mary Wheeler; Henry C. Whitehead; Winston Wilkinson; Edward C. Wurtele to Francis Rogers.
        Letters from John Powell to: F. C. Adler; John Blakemore; Mrs. Boocock; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Miss [Elsie] Illingworth; Mr. [George] Fischer; Mr. [Alexander] Haas; Mr. Keppel; Ernest LaPrade; Marks Levine; Mr. Moore; John Lloyd Newcomb; Mrs. Repass; Mr. [George] Schaun; Lamar Stringfield.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: Council Cruise; Mrs. Strickler.
      - Correspondence, September-October 1935, 90 items. (Box-folder 11:4)
        Correspondents include J. [Aulebez], G. Schirmer, Inc.; J.H. Binford; John Blakemore to Richard Crane; Antonia Brico; Eddy Brown; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Richard Chase; Elizabeth M. Copping; Virginia Chevalier Cork; Richard Crane; Edwin Feller; Anis Fuleihan, G. Schirmer, Inc.; Charles E. Griffith; C. C. Guthrie, Greenville County Music Club; Sidney B. Hall to George B. Zehmer; Cornelia G. Hancock; L. Dudley Heinrich to Dr. Sidney B. Hall; George Herzog; Elsie Illingworth; George Pullen Jackson; Ernest LaPrade to Mrs. Stires; Mr. Lewis; Arnold L. Lovejoy; [Margaret]; Russell Means; Dorothy Meyer; Harold D. Meyer; Josephine Milnot; H. T. Nostrand, Jr.; Ashley Pettis; J. Albert Riker; Audre [Skalski]; Nikolai Sokoloff; James P. C. Southall, Mrs. Sallie B. Steele; Lamar Stringfield; Mercye Tucker; H. T. Von Nostrand, Jr.; Henry C. Whitehead; Marie and Winston Wilkinson; George B. Zehmer.